[
    {
        "question": "What is the nothernmost provincial capital?",
        "answer": "Edmonton"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river runs through both Lyon and Marseilles?",
        "answer": "Rhone River"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approximately how long is the Congo River?",
        "answer": "2,900 miles"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the three colors in the Jamaican flag?",
        "answer": "Black, green and yellow"
    },
    {
        "question": "Machu Picchu is also known as what?",
        "answer": "Lost City of the Incas"
    },
    {
        "question": "`Lost City of the Incas` is another name for what Peruvian site?",
        "answer": "Machu Picchu"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city in Ohio is known as the `Queen City`?",
        "answer": "Cincinnati"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cape May is located on which US coast?",
        "answer": "East coast"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which US state can one visit the Appomattox Court House National Historical Park?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Oregon`s Mount Hood is located in what mountain chain?",
        "answer": "Cascade Mountains"
    },
    {
        "question": "Warsaw is the capital of what country?",
        "answer": "Poland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Warsaw is the capital of which European country?",
        "answer": "Poland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What mountain chain runs from Maine to Alabama?",
        "answer": "Appalachian Mountains"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which flag becomes the flag of Poland when turned upside down?",
        "answer": "Indonesia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Bavaria?",
        "answer": "Munich"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest desert in the U.S.?",
        "answer": "Great Basin Desert"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the Asian nation of Myanmar known as prior to 1989?",
        "answer": "Burma"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country is the Waterloo battlefield?",
        "answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which modern day country would you find the region known as Transylvania?",
        "answer": "Romania"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which continent would you find the Mackenzie river? ",
        "answer": "North America"
    },
    {
        "question": "Saginaw Bay opens into what body of water?",
        "answer": "Lake Huron"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is located directly west of Louisiana?",
        "answer": "Texas"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US city was once called New Amsterdam?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river separates Maryland and Virginia?",
        "answer": "Potomac River"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is closest to Cuba?",
        "answer": "Florida"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most common ending for a city, town, village or hamlet in England?",
        "answer": "-ton"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country`s name is the local pronunciation of the name of its British discoverer, Thomas Gilbert?",
        "answer": "Kiribati"
    },
    {
        "question": "What lake is located several miles west of Carson City?",
        "answer": "Lake Tahoe"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Welsh name for Mount Snowdon?",
        "answer": "Yr Wyddfa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which European country replaced the Tolar with the Euro?",
        "answer": "Slovenia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which European country replaced the Kroon with the Euro?",
        "answer": "Estonia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What largest lake of Central America is home to unusual freshwater sharks?",
        "answer": "Lake Nicaragua"
    },
    {
        "question": "In terms of land area, what are the three largest countries bordering China to the north?",
        "answer": "Russia, Mongolia and Kazakhstan"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many territories does the US administer over?",
        "answer": "16"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which South American country takes its name from Christopher Columbus?",
        "answer": "Colombia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only US state with a single syllable name?",
        "answer": "Maine"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is US`s largest state by land area?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Sumter?",
        "answer": "South Carolina"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Knox?",
        "answer": "Kentucky"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Leavenworth?",
        "answer": "Kansas"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Wayne?",
        "answer": "Indiana"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort McHenry?",
        "answer": "Maryland"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Ticonderoga?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the white part of the Colorado state flag represent?",
        "answer": "Snow-capped mountains -- Designed by Andrew Carlisle Johnson in 1911, the flag`s colors represent different aspects of Arizona."
    },
    {
        "question": "What flower is featured on Mississippi`s new state flag?",
        "answer": "Magnolia -- The flag plays homage to the state`s status as the Magnolia State, featuring a bright white magnolia flower."
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Hood?",
        "answer": "Texas"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Dix?",
        "answer": "New Jersey"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Bragg?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the only two South American countries that do not border Brazil?",
        "answer": "Chile and Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the capital city of West Germany from 1949 to 1990?",
        "answer": "Bonn"
    }
]